TAYLOR GARREY

Mesa, AZ 85204

Phone: 480-322-2698 | Email: tgarrey37@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>Taylor Garrey</u> GitHub: <u>Tgarrey37</u> Portfolio: <u>Taylor Garrey Portfolio</u>

SUMMARY

Full-Stack web developer utilizing my experience with personal communication, to help people with their online presence. Recently Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Arizona Coding Boot Camp. Developed skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQI, and MERN stacks. Passionate about developing responsive web pages and apps for the user to have the best experience. Continuously work through problems and obstacles until they are fixed and up to the users standard. Provide professional communication to collaborate with a team. Worked on a team multiple times working with Git, to create responsive applications. Projects were created using Javascript and MERN to make a polished application. Determined to provide problem solving, dedication, and attentiveness to any team in the field.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Github, Gitlab, Visual Studio Code, Git, Insomnia, Postman. Current, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, mySQL, JQuery, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mern, React.js.

PROJECTS

Last Minute Trip Planner

Deployed Project: <u>Last Minute Trip Planner</u> Github Repository: <u>Last Minute Trip Planner</u>

- The functionality gives you the ability to select your days of your trip up to a week. The application will show you local restaurants, attractions and hotels.
- Core responsibility was to help make the API fetches for the travel API. Also involved on helping with CSS styling and HTML layouts.
- Languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, and a 3rd party Web API.

Baby Yelp

Deployed Project: <u>Baby Yelp</u> Github Repository: <u>Baby Yelp</u>

- This application is a restaurant review website. You can select from the top 10 restaurants in the world and leave a review for them.
- Languages used: Javascript, CSS and Handlebars for the HTML template.

Code Quiz

Deployed Project: <u>Code Quiz</u> Github Repository: <u>Code Quiz</u>

- This application is a Javascript Code Quiz.
- Role was to complete the entire application.
- Languages used: Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

EXPERIENCE

Community Relations Specialist Modern Recovery Services

2020 – 2021 Mesa. Az

While at Modern Recovery established professional relationships working community outreach. Continuously contacted and connected with 15 clients a day to help them with substance use and mental health. Worked closely with other business development roles at other companies to promote Modern Recovery. Enrolled over 50 clients into Modern Recovery to better help them manage life.

Accomplishments:

- Facilitated a group a week for at risk teens struggling with mental health.
- Contributed to enrolling over 50 clients into mental health care.
- Created professional relationships with companies in the field to build business.

Peer Support Specialist notMYkid

2017-2020

Scottsdale, AZ

The main responsibility was helping Adolescents with substance use disorder, and mental health struggles. Facilitated groups with adolescents and their families. Traveled all across Arizona to speak at high schools. Shared on the dangers of Substance Use and not practicing self care.

Accomplishments:

- Helped Adolescents with Substance Use Disorder.
- Spoke to 45,000 students on mental health.
- Lead groups with over 300 families and students.
- Showed hundreds of students a new way of life.

Inbound Sales Associate GoDaddy

2016 - 2017

Gilbert, AZ

Provided excellent customer service and technical support for small business websites. Assisted companies with their websites and hosting. Sold Domains, Hosting, and Office 365.

Accomplishments:

- Learned knowledge of DNS and Websites.
- Excelled at customer service communication.
- Sold countless websites and domain names.
- Developed rapport with customers.

Sales Associate TCC Verizon Wireless

2015 - 2016

Scottsdale, AZ

Sold cell phones and Verizon plans to in need customers. Greeted customers upon entrance of the establishment and assessed their needs. Helped with countless tech problems and obstacles. Monthly continued to become a top sales associate in my local area.

Accomplishments:

- Solved technology issues on mobile devices.
- Provided value to sell the newest cell phone technology.
- Established a clean and orderly store for customers and co-workers.
- Acquired extensive mobile technology understanding.
- Awarded top sales of the local area Verizon stores.

EDUCATION

University of Arizona Full Stack Web Development Certificate:

 A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS. I expect to graduate on March 2nd 2022.